nitie.edu 2017-07-03

# NITIE PRIVACY POLICY 014/01/c

                                          NITIE PRIVACY POLICY
                                                 014/01/c
This document is an electronic record in terms of information technology laws as amended and in
force in India. The said electronic record is computer generated and does not require any
authentication.
Introduction
NITIE will not sell, rent or forward your personal and other information shared in order to avail any of
the services and or use of NITIE’s website to any of the third party for any purpose. This statement of
privacy is applicable under the domain name(s) www.nitie.edu and www.nitie.ac.in and all related sub
domain names that the user logs. Your use of NITIE’s website(s) signifies the acceptance of NITIE’s
privacy statement. NITIE strives to comply with the applicable Indian laws that are designed to protect
your privacy. Any interpretation of the terms of this privacy policy shall be in accordance with the said
‘terms of use’.
Principles of Privacy Protection
NITIE’s privacy policy is developed on the following tenets:
    1. Privacy of the user (login) is of utmost priority.
    2. Privacy of the user (login) is valuable.
The following set of principles are followed by NITIE to ensure privacy of its users:
    1.   Notification
    2.   User choice
    3.   Security
    4.   Access accuracy
Notification
NITIE intends to post a statement of purpose explaining the need to collect personal information on
its website. This statement would include whether NITIE intends to share information so collected
outside of NITIE or with those working as authorised representative or on behalf of NITIE. NITIE does
not intend to transfer any of the user’s personal information to any of the party not bound to act on
behalf of NITIE without prior permission, unless such transfer of information is legally required.
Access accuracy
NITIE intends to maintain accurate information that is required to better use and provide its domain
services. To the extent that the user provides personal information, NITIE aims to provide a means for
the user to contact for update or correction of such information. In the absence due to unavailability
or inaccessibility for such update services, the user may send the modified personal information to
NITIE for it to take reasonable efforts to incorporate the changes.
User choice
You, the user may choose to provide or not to provide the personal information to NITIE. While the
NITIE website is accessible to anyone, the further use of certain options, services and activities is
restricted to those users who provide the information as requested by NITIE. NITIE would use the

information provided for any appropriate contacts in connection to the services of NITIE chosen to be
availed.
Consent
By continuing to use this website, you consent to the terms of NITIE’s privacy policy and to the
processing of the personal information so shared for the purposes given above. In case of specific
requirements of your personal details, NITIE would try to communicate (but not obligated) at the time
of collection, the intended use of the personal information. Your personal information so collected by
NITIE are used only to respond for inquiries or other individual processes that might require a response
by you (the concerned party) or allow access to your specific account information.
Disclosure of User Information
NITIE would appropriately share the collected user information for the purpose of alumni and or
academic interaction both with and amongst the relevant applicants.
Affiliated Sites
For the purpose of providing specific services to our site like online payments, NITIE has affiliated with
certain third parties. Your personal information provided to the affiliated sites may be shared with
NITIE for further processing and delivering the appropriate service and or response from NITIE. Such
information shared are processed in accordance with this privacy policy along with the different
privacy policies of the appropriate service provider. The user is required to read all the related privacy
policies.
Cookies
Cookies are small bits of information that are stored in your system while accessing NITIE website. The
cookies so installed shall be exclusively used for the purpose of retrieving information and content
relevant for you, relate with services that pertains to be useful for the purpose of completing the
service required from NITIE. These cookies shall have limited scope in terms of time for the purpose
of student enrolment for admission to NITIE.
Changes in Privacy Policy
Please note that this privacy policy may change from time to time. NITIE will not reduce your rights
under this policy without your explicit consent. NITIE expects at most minor modifications to the
privacy policy over time.
Questions or Suggestions
If you have any questions related to NITIE’s privacy policy, collection, use or disclosure of your personal
information, please contact NITIE at nitiedracademic@nitie.edu
NITIE reserves the right to change, modify and update this privacy statement at any time without
individual notice.
